I published this article
لقد نشرتُ هذه المقالة
in the New York Times Modern Love column in January of this year.
بصحيفة نيويورك تايمز بقسم الحب العصري في يناير من هذا العام.
"To Fall in Love With Anyone, Do This."
"للوقوع في الحبّ مع أيّ شخص، قُم بالآتي."
And the article is about a psychological study
وتندرج هذ المقالة ضمن دراسة نفسية
designed to create romantic love in the laboratory,
تهدف إلى خلق حب رومانسي بالمختبر،
and my own experience trying the study myself
وتجربتي الخاصة مُحاولة دراسة نفسي
one night last summer.
في أحد الليالي في الصيف الفائت.
So the procedure is fairly simple:
إذن العمليّة سهلة إلى حدّ ما:
two strangers take turns asking each other 36 increasingly personal questions
سيتناوب غريبين على طرح 36 سؤالا على بعضهم البعض
and then they stare into each other's eyes
وثمّ يُحدّقون في أعين بعضهم البعض
without speaking for four minutes.
من دون أن يتكلموا لمدة 4 دقائق.
So here are a couple of sample questions.
وهذه عينة من بعض الأسئلة:
Number 12: If you could wake up tomorrow having gained any one quality or ability,
رقم 12: اذا استيقظت في الغد وقد اكتسبت قدرة جديدة،
what would it be?
ماذا ستكون؟
Number 28: When did you last cry in front of another person?
رقم28: متى بكيت آخر مرّة أمام شخص آخر؟
By yourself?
وبمفردك؟
As you can see, they really do get more personal as they go along.
كما تُلاحظون، الأسئلة تُصبح شخصية أكثر؟
Number 30, I really like this one:
رقم30، حقا يُعجبني هذا السؤال:
Tell your partner what you like about them;
أخبر شريكك ما الذي تُحبّذه فيه،
be very honest this time,
ولكن بشكل صريح هذه المرّة،
saying things you might not say to someone you just met.
ستقول أشياء لم تتجرّأ على قولها لشخص قابلته لأوّل مرّة
So when I first came across this study a few years earlier,
اذن عندما صادفت هذه الدراسة قبل بضع سنوات،
one detail really stuck out to me,
علق بذاكرتي حقّا أحد التفاصيل،
and that was the rumor that two of the participants
حيث شاع خبر زواج مشاركين
had gotten married six months later,
بعد ستة أشهر،
and they'd invited the entire lab to the ceremony.
وقاموا بدعوة الجميع بالمختبر.
So I was of course very skeptical
اذن كان لدي بالطبع بعض الشكوك
about this process of just manufacturing romantic love,
حول هذه العملية أي مجرد تصنيع الحب الرومانسي،
but of course I was intrigued.
ولكن بالطبع كنت مفتونة.
And when I got the chance to try this study myself,
وعندما أُتيحت لي الفرصة لتجربة هذه الدراسة بنفسي،
with someone I knew but not particularly well,
بصحبة شخص أعرفه ولكن ليس حقّ المعرفة،
I wasn't expecting to fall in love.
لم أكن أتوقع الوقوع في الحب.
But then we did, and --
ولكن حصل ذلك، و--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I thought it made a good story, so I sent it to the Modern Love column
وظننت أنها قصة جيدة، فأرسلتها إلى قسم الحب العصري
a few months later.
بعد بضعة أشهر.
Now, this was published in January,
والآن، قد تم نشرها في يناير،
and now it is August,
والآن أغسطس،
so I'm guessing that some of you are probably wondering,
إذن أعتقد أن البعض منكم يتساءلون،
are we still together?
هل مازلنا مع بعضنا البعض؟
And the reason I think you might be wondering this
والسبب وراء اعتقادي بأنكم تتساءلون
is because I have been asked this question
لأنه تم طرح هذا السؤال عديد المرات
again and again and again for the past seven months.
مرارا وتكرارا خلال الأشهر السبع الماضية.
And this question is really what I want to talk about today.
وهذا السؤال هو ما أريد التحدث عنه اليوم.
But let's come back to it.
ولكن لنرجع إليه أولا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So the week before the article came out,
إذن في الأسبوع السابق لإصدار المقال،
I was very nervous.
كنت متشنجة كثيرا.
I had been working on a book about love stories
كنت أعمل على كتاب يتمحور حول قصص الحب
for the past few years,
خلال الأعوام الماضية،
so I had gotten used to writing about my own experiences
لذلك كنت معتادة على الكتابة حول تجاربي الخاصة
with romantic love on my blog.
المتعلّقة بالحب الرومنسي على مدوّنتي.
But a blog post might get a couple hundred views at the most,
ولكن يُمكن أن تحظى مقالة على المدوّنة بالمتابعة من قبل مئات الأشخاص،
and those were usually just my Facebook friends,
وهؤلاء كانوا دائما أصدقائي على موقع الفايسبوك،
and I figured my article in the New York Times
ولقد تفطنت بأن مقالتي بصحيفة نيويورك تايمز
would probably get a few thousand views.
ستحظى بمتابعة الآلاف من الأشخاص.
And that felt like a lot of attention
ويُعتبر هذا كثيرا من الإهتمام
on a relatively new relationship.
حول علاقة جديدة نسبيا.
But as it turned out, I had no idea.
ولكن كما اتضح فما بعد، لم يكن لدي أي فكرة.
So the article was published online
اذن تم نشر المقال على الأنترنت
on a Friday evening,
مساء الجمعة،
and by Saturday, this had happened to the traffic on my blog.
ويوم السبت، هذا ما حصل على مدوّنتي.
And by Sunday, both the Today Show and Good Morning America had called.
ويوم الأحد تلقيت اتصالات من قبل برنامج " برنامج اليوم" و "صباح الخيرأمريكا"
Within a month, the article would receive over 8 million views,
وفي ظرف شهر، حظيت مقالتي بمتابعة 8 مليون شخص،
and I was, to say the least,
وباختصار لم أكن،
underprepared for this sort of attention.
مستعدّة لكلّ هذا الاهتمام.
It's one thing to work up the confidence to write honestly
هذا مُحفّز للكتابة بصراحة
about your experiences with love,
حول تجاربك الخاصة في الحب،
but it is another thing to discover
ولكن اكتشاف شيء آخر
that your love life has made international news --
وهو أن حياتك العاطفية أصبحت في الأخبار العالمية --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
and to realize that people across the world
وأن تكتشف بأن الناس في أنحاء العالم
are genuinely invested in the status of your new relationship.
يستثمرون حقا في حالة علاقتك الجديدة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And when people called or emailed, which they did every day for weeks,
وعندما يتصل الأشخاص أو يرسلون بريدا الكترونيا، وهو ما قاموا به كل يوم،
they always asked the same question first:
دائما ما يسألون نفس السؤال أولا:
are you guys still together?
هل مازلتم معا؟
In fact, as I was preparing this talk,
في الحقيقة، بينما كنت أستعد لهذه المحادثة،
I did a quick search of my email inbox
قمت ببحث سريع في صندوقي البريدي
for the phrase "Are you still together?"
لجملة "هل مازلتم معا؟"
and several messages popped up immediately.
وبرزت عدة رسائل على الفور.
They were from students and journalists
من قبل طلبة وصحافيين
and friendly strangers like this one.
غرباء ودودين مثل هذه.
I did radio interviews and they asked.
لقد قمت بمقابلات إذاعية وسألوني.
I even gave a talk, and one woman shouted up to the stage,
قمت بمحادثة وقامت امرأة بالصراخ على المسرح،
"Hey Mandy, where's your boyfriend?"
"يا ماندي، أين حبيبك؟"
And I promptly turned bright red.
وأصبح وجهي أحمرا على الفور.
I understand that this is part of the deal.
أتفهم بأن هذا جزء من الصفقة.
If you write about your relationship in an international newspaper,
اذا كتبت عن علاقتك بصحيفة عالمية،
you should expect people to feel comfortable asking about it.
فينبغي عليك أن تتوقع أخذ الجميع راحتهم للسؤال عن ذلك.
But I just wasn't prepared for the scope of the response.
لكنني لم أكن مستعدة للإجابة.
The 36 questions seem to have taken on a life of their own.
يبدو أن 36 سؤالا لم يعد بالإمكان التحكم بهم.
In fact, the New York Times published a follow-up article
في الحقيقة، نشرت صحيفة نيويورك تايمز مقالا للمتابعة
for Valentine's Day,
لعيد الحب،
which featured readers' experiences of trying the study themselves,
والذي كشف عن تجارب القُرّاء لهذه الدراسة بأنفسهم،
with varying degrees of success.
بدرجات متفاوتة من النجاح.
So my first impulse in the face of all of this attention
إذن كان دافعي الأول لمواجهة كل هذا الإهتمام
was to become very protective of my own relationship.
أن أُصبح أكثر حذرا في حماية علاقتي الخاصة.
I said no to every request for the two of us
ولقد رفضت كل طلب
to do a media appearance together.
للقيام بظهور إعلامي معا.
I turned down TV interviews,
امتنعت عن المقابلات التلفازية،
and I said no to every request for photos of the two us.
ورفضت كل طلب لصورنا معا.
I think I was afraid that we would become
أعتقد بأنني كنت مُتخوّفة من أن نُصبح
inadvertent icons for the process of falling in love,
رموزا مقصودة لعملية الوقوع في الحب،
a position I did not at all feel qualified for.
وهي مكانة لا أعتقد بأنني مُؤهلة لها.
And I get it:
ولقد فهمت:
people didn't just want to know if the study worked,
أن الأشخاص لا يريدون فقط معرفة ما إذا كانت العملية ناجحة،
they wanted to know if it really worked:
بل هل نجحت العملية حقّا:
that is, if it was capable of producing love that would last,
يعني هل كانت هناك القدرة على إنتاج حبّ دائم،
not just a fling, but real love, sustainable love.
ليس فقط توليد حب، ولكن حب حقيقي، حب مستمر.
But this was a question I didn't feel capable of answering.
ولكن كان هذا سؤال لم أشعر بقدرتي على الإجابة عليه.
My own relationship was only a few months old,
علاقتي لم تكن سوى منذ بضعة أشهر،
and I felt like people were asking the wrong question in the first place.
ولقد شعرت بأن السؤال لم يكن في محله في الوهلة الأولى.
What would knowing whether or not we were still together really tell them?
ما هي أهميّة معرفة ما إذا كنا ما نزال معا بالنسبة لهم؟
If the answer was no,
إذا كانت الإجابة بلا،
would it make the experience of doing these 36 questions
فهل سيجعل هذا من تجربة 36 سؤالا
any less worthwhile?
تجربة أقل شأنا؟
Dr. Arthur Aron first wrote about these questions
أول كتابة للدكتور آرثر حول هذه الأسئلة
in this study here in 1997,
لهذه الدراسة كانت في سنة 1997،
and here, the researcher's goal was not to produce romantic love.
وهنا لم يكن هدف الباحثين خلق حب رومانسي.
Instead, they wanted to foster
بدلا من ذلك، أرادوا تعزيز
interpersonal closeness among college students,
العلاقات بين طلبة الجامعات،
by using what Aron called
باستعمال ما سماه آرون
"sustained, escalating, reciprocal, personalistic self-disclosure."
"كشف عن الذات، مستمر، متزايد، متبادل، و شخصي "
Sounds romantic, doesn't it?
يبدو رومنسيا، أليس كذلك؟
But the study did work.
ولكن الدراسة نجحت.
The participants did feel closer after doing it,
فلقد شعر المشاركون بقربهم من بعضهم البعض بعد تجربة هذا،
and several subsequent studies have also used Aron's fast friends protocol
واستعملت العديد من الدراسات اللاحقة بروتوكول آرون
as a way to quickly create trust and intimacy between strangers.
كوسيلة لخلق نوع من الثقة والحميمية بين الغرباء.
They've used it between members of the police and members of community,
لقد استعملوه بين أفراد الشرطة والمجتمع،
and they've used it between people of opposing political ideologies.
وكذلك بين الناس ذوي إيديولوجيات سياسية مختلفة.
The original version of the story,
النسخة الأصلية للقصة،
the one that I tried last summer,
تلك التي قمت بتجربتها الصيف الماضي،
that pairs the personal questions with four minutes of eye contact,
والتي كانت مجموعة من الأسئلة مصحوبة بأربعة دقائق من تبادل النظرات،
was referenced in this article,
والتي تمت الإشارة إليها في هذا المقال،
but unfortunately it was never published.
ولكن للأسف لم يتم نشرها.
So a few months ago, I was giving a talk
اذن منذ عدة أشهر، كنت ألقي مُحادثة
at a small liberal arts college,
بكليّة صغيرة للفنون الحرّة،
and a student came up to me afterwards
قدم إليّ طالب فيما بعد
and he said, kind of shyly,
وقال لي بخجل،
"So, I tried your study, and it didn't work."
"لقد جربت دراستك ولكنها لم تنجح."
He seemed a little mystified by this.
بدت عليه الحيرة بسبب هذا.
"You mean, you didn't fall in love with the person you did it with?" I asked.
"تعني بأنك لم تقع في حبّ الشخص الذي قمت معه بالتجربة؟" سألته.
"Well..." He paused.
"في الحقيقة...." توقف لبرهة.
"I think she just wants to be friends."
"أعتقد أنها تريد أن نبقى أصدقاء فقط."
"But did you become better friends?" I asked.
"ولكن هل أصبحتم أصدقاء أفضل؟" سألته.
"Did you feel like you got to really know each other after doing the study?"
"هل شعرت برغبة في معرفة المزيد عن بعضكم البعض بعد تجربة الدراسة؟"
He nodded.
أومأ برأسه.
"So, then it worked," I said.
"اذن، لقد نجحت،" قلت له.
I don't think this is the answer he was looking for.
لا أعتقد بأن هذه الإجابة التي كان في انتظارها.
In fact, I don't think this is the answer that any of us are looking for
بل، لا أعتقد بأنه هذه الإجابة التي ينتظرها أي منا
when it comes to love.
عندما يتعلق الأمر بالحب.
I first came across this study
لقد اكتشفت هذه الدراسة
when I was 29
عندما كنت في 29 من عمري
and I was going through a really difficult breakup.
ولقد كانت حالتي صعبة بعد انفصالي عن حبيبي.
I had been in the relationship since I was 20,
لقد كنت في هذه العلاقة منذ أن كان عمري 20 سنة،
which was basically my entire adult life,
وبالتالي طوال فترة المراهقة،
and he was my first real love,
ولقد كان حبي الأوّل الحقيقي،
and I had no idea how or if I could make a life without him.
ولم تكن لدي أدنى فكرة عن كيفية العيش بدونه.
So I turned to science.
لذلك انشغلت بالعلوم.
I researched everything I could find about the science of romantic love,
قمت بالبحث حول كل ما يتعلق بعلم الحب الرومنسي،
and I think I was hoping that it might somehow inoculate me from heartache.
وكنت على أمل بأن أتعافى من وجع القلب.
I don't know if I realized this at the time --
ولا أعرف هل أدركت ذلك حينها أم لا --
I thought I was just doing research for this book I was writing --
ظننت بأنني أقوم بالبحث فقط لكي أكتب كتابي --
but it seems really obvious in retrospect.
ولكن يبدو حقا واضحا عند الإلتفات إلى أحداث الماضي.
I hoped that if I armed myself with the knowledge of romantic love,
تمنيت لو كنت مسلّحة بمعرفة الحب الرومانسي،
I might never have to feel as terrible and lonely as I did then.
لما شعرت أبدا بالوحدة كما حدث معي آنذاك.
And all this knowledge has been useful in some ways.
وكل هذه المعرفة كانت مفيدة بعدة طرق.
I am more patient with love. I am more relaxed.
أنا أكثر صبرً في ما يتعلق بالحب. أكثر استرخاءً.
I am more confident about asking for what I want.
وأكثر ثقة عند طلب ما أريده.
But I can also see myself more clearly,
ولكن يمكن أن أرى نفسي بوضوح أكثر،
and I can see that what I want is sometimes more
وأستطيع أن أعترف بأن ما أريده في بعض الأحيان
than can reasonably be asked for.
هو أكثر من المعقول.
What I want from love is a guarantee,
ما أريده من الحب أن يكون مضمونا،
not just that I am loved today
ليس فقط بأن تُحبّني اليوم فقط
and that I will be loved tomorrow,
وأنك ستحبني غدا،
but that I will continue to be loved by the person I love indefinitely.
ولكن أن يُحبّني الشخص إلى أجل غير مسمّى.
Maybe it's this possibility of a guarantee
ربما هذا الاحتمال من الضمان
that people were really asking about
الذي كان يسأل عنه الناس حقا
when they wanted to know if we were still together.
عندما كانوا يريدون معرفة ما إذا كنا نزال معا.
So the story that the media told about the 36 questions
اذن القصة االتي عرضتها وسائل الإعلام حول 36 سؤالا
was that there might be a shortcut to falling in love.
أنه قد يكون هناك طريقة مختصرة للوقوع في الحب.
There might be a way to somehow mitigate some of the risk involved,
ربما توجد طريقة ما للتخفيف من بعض المخاطر التي تنطوي عليها،
and this is a very appealing story,
وهذه قصة جذابة جدا،
because falling in love feels amazing,
لأن الوقوع في الحب مذهل،
but it's also terrifying.
ولكن مخيف في نفس الوقت.
The moment you admit to loving someone,
في اللحظة التي تعترف بحب شخص ما،
you admit to having a lot to lose,
ستعترف بخسارة الكثير،
and it's true that these questions do provide a mechanism
صحيح بأن هذه الأسئلة توفر طريقة
for getting to know someone quickly,
لمعرفة شخص ما بسرعة،
which is also a mechanism for being known,
وهي طريقة للتعريف بنفسك،
and I think this is the thing that most of us really want from love:
وأظن أن هذا ما يريده حقا كل منا من الحب:
to be known, to be seen, to be understood.
أن تتم معرفتنا ورؤيتنا وفهمنا.
But I think when it comes to love,
ولكن عندما يتعلق الأمر بالحب،
we are too willing to accept the short version of the story.
أظن بأننا على استعداد لقبول النسخة القصيرة من القصة.
The version of the story that asks, "Are you still together?"
النسخة من القصة التي تحتوي على الأسئلة التالية، "هل مازلتم مع بعضكم البعض؟"
and is content with a yes or no answer.
ومحتوى الإجابة بنعم أو لا.
So rather than that question,
إذن عوض ذلك السؤال،
I would propose we ask some more difficult questions,
أقترح أن نسأل أسئلة أكثر صعوبة،
questions like:
أسئلة مثل:
How do you decide who deserves your love
كيف تُقرّر من يستحقّ حبّك
and who does not?
ومن لا يستحقّه؟
How do you stay in love when things get difficult,
كيف تُحافظ على حبك عندما تشتد الأمور،
and how do you know when to just cut and run?
ومتى تعرف بأنه عليك التوقف والرحيل؟
How do you live with the doubt
كيف تعيش مع الشك الذي دائما
that inevitably creeps into every relationship,
ما يُحيط أي علاقة،
or even harder,
أو أصعب من ذلك،
how do you live with your partner's doubt?
كيف تتعايش مع شكوك حبيبك؟
I don't necessarily know the answers to these questions,
أنا لا أعرف بالضرورة الإجابات على كلّ هذه الأسئلة،
but I think they're an important start at having a more thoughtful conversation
ولكن أظن بأنهم يُمثلون بداية مهمة لمحادثة أكثر عمقا
about what it means to love someone.
حول ما يعنيه أن تُحبّ شخصا ما.
So, if you want it,
إذن، إذا أردتم ذلك،
the short version of the story of my relationship is this:
النسخة القصيرة لقصة علاقتي هي التالية:
a year ago, an acquaintance and I did a study
قبل عام قمت أنا وشخص أعرفه بدراسة
designed to create romantic love,
تهدف لخلق حب رومانسي،
and we fell in love,
ووقعنا في الحب،
and we are still together,
ومازلنا معا،
and I am so glad.
وأنا سعيدة جدا.
But falling in love is not the same thing as staying in love.
ولكن الوقوع في الحب والمحافظة عليه شيء مختلف تماما.
Falling in love is the easy part.
الوقوع في الحب هو الجزء السهل.
So at the end of my article, I wrote, "Love didn't happen to us.
لذلك كتبت في ختام مقالتي، "الحب لا يحدث لنا.
We're in love because we each made the choice to be."
نحن في الحب لأننا اخترنا ذلك."
And I cringe a little when I read that now,
وأشعر بالذلّ قليلا عندما أقرأ ذلك الآن،
not because it isn't true,
ليس بسبب عدم صحّة ذلك،
but because at the time, I really hadn't considered
ولكن لأنني في ذلك الوقت، لم آخذ في عين الإعتبار
everything that was contained in that choice.
كل شيء مُتعلّق بذلك الإختيار.
I didn't consider how many times we would each have to make that choice,
لم آخذ في عين الإعتبار عدد المرات التي سنقوم فيها بذلك الاختيار،
and how many times I will continue to have to make that choice
وعدد المرات التي سأكمل فيها القيام بذلك الإختيار
without knowing whether or not he will always choose me.
من دون أن أعرف إن كان سيختارني في كلّ مرّة أو لا.
I want it to be enough to have asked and answered 36 questions,
أريد أن يكون السؤال والإجابة على 36 سؤالا كافيا،
and to have chosen to love someone so generous and kind and fun
واختيار أن تحب شخصا بكرم وشغف ومرح كافيا
and to have broadcast that choice in the biggest newspaper in America.
وأن تنشر اختيارك بأكبر صحيفة بأمريكا.
But what I have done instead is turn my relationship
ولكن الذي قمت به عوض ذلك هو تحويل علاقتي
into the kind of myth I don't quite believe in.
إلى نوع من الأسطورة التي لا أؤمن بها جدا.
And what I want, what perhaps I will spend my life wanting,
وما الذي أريده أو ربما أقضي حياتي كاملة وأنا أريده،
is for that myth to be true.
هو أن تُصبح هذه الأسطورة حقيقية.
I want the happy ending implied by the title to my article,
أريد أن يشمل عنوان مقالتي جملة "نهاية سعيدة"،
which is, incidentally,
وهو بالمناسبة،
the only part of the article that I didn't actually write.
الجزء الوحيد من المقال الذي لم أكتبه.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But what I have instead is the chance to make the choice to love someone,
ولكن ما الذي أملكه بدلا من ذلك هو فرصة اختيار أن تحب أحدهم،
and the hope that he will choose to love me back,
والأمل في أن يُحبّني هو أيضا
and it is terrifying,
وهذا مخيف،
but that's the deal with love.
لكن هذه هي صفقة الحب.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.